United Nations Collection of Kofi Annan Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
United Nations collection of Kofi Annan papers
1997-2007
MS 1925
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10.5
(21 boxes)
The collection consists of copies of select Annan papers from the United Nations, including interviews, correspondence, briefings, reports and speeches from Annan's tenure as United Nations Secretary-General from 1997 to 2007. The majority of the papers in this collection are published and indexed in the Collected Papers of Kofi Annan, UN Secretary-General, 1997-2006, edited by Jean E. Krasno.
Annan, Kofi A. (Kofi Atta), 1938-
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by type of material.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of copies of select Annan papers from the United Nations, including interviews, correspondence, briefings, reports and speeches from Annan's tenure as United Nations Secretary-General from 1997 to 2007. The majority of the papers in this collection are published and indexed in the Collected Papers of Kofi Annan, UN Secretary-General, 1997-2006, edited by Jean E. Krasno.
Existence and Location of Originals
Originals are in the United Nations, Archives and Records Management Section.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the United Nations, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Kofi Atta Annan was born in Kumasi, Ghana, on April 8, 1938. He earned degrees from Macalester College in St. Paul, Minnesota (1961); the Graduate Institute of International Studies (Geneva); and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in Cambridge, Massachusetts (1971-1972). Annan began his career with the United Nations in 1962 and held various posts, including Deputy Director to the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (1980-1983) and Under-Secretary-General for Peacekeeping (1995-1996). Annan was the first Secretary-General chosen from the ranks of the United Nations staff, serving in that post from 1997 to 2006. In 2001 Annan and the United Nations were awarded the Nobel Peace Prize for their ongoing work in global peace and cooperation.
International cooperation; Security, International; Annan, Kofi A. (Kofi Atta), 1938-; United Nations; United Nations. Secretary-General
- Interviews, 1997-2006 (Box 1, Folder 1-8)
- Correspondence to and from the Secretary General and Security Council, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- Noon briefings
  - 1997 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - 2000-2002 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - 2003-2004 July (Box 4, Folder 1-6)
  - 2004 August-2006 (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
- Off-The-Cuff
  - 1998-2002 (Box 6, Folder 1-8)
  - 2002-2005 (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
- Op-eds, 1998-2006 (Box 7, Folder 6-14)
- Presentations to the General Assembly, 1998-2006 (Box 8, Folder 1-9)
- Presentations to the Security Council, 1998-2006 (Box 8, Folder 10-18)
- Press conferences, 1997-2006 (Box 9, Folder 1-10)
- Press release statements
  - 1997-2004 (Box 10, Folder 1-10)
  - 2005-2006 (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
- Private correspondence
  - 1997-1998 July (Box 11, Folder 5-8)
  - 1998 August-2002 May (Box 12, Folder 1-8)
  - 2002 June-2003 June (Box 13, Folder 1-6)
  - 2003 July-2004 June (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
  - 2004 July-2005 June (Box 15, Folder 1-5)
  - 2005 July-2006 July (Box 16, Folder 1-7)
  - 2006 August-2007 (Box 17, Folder 1-5)
- Private correspondence to the President of the Security Council, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Reports of the General Assembly
  - 1997-2000 (Box 17, Folder 7-10)
  - 2001-2006 (Box 18, Folder 1-7)
- Report to the General Assembly and Security Council, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Reports to the Security Council
  - 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 9-10)
  - 1999-2005 (Box 19, Folder 1-7)
- Speeches
  - 1997-1998 May (Box 19, Folder 8-11)
  - 1998 June-2001 (Box 20, Folder 1-8)
  - 2002-2006 (Box 21, Folder 1-7)